#### **BEN SBANOTTO**

Tulsa, Oklahoma <u>ben.sbanotto@gmail.com</u>
(479)-409-6910 <u>www.linkedin.com/in/ben-sbanotto/</u>
www.bensbanotto.com <u>www.github.com/bsbanotto</u>

### **Profile**

Professional with 10+ years of experience using data to identify problems across various manufacturing industries to implement sustainable solutions. Excited to combine professional and technical team leadership experience with a robust technical skill set to add immediate value and ensure company success.

#### Skills

**Languages:** Linux, Bash, C, Python, MySQL, SQLAlchemy, CV2, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Minitab, Jupyter Notebook, Pandas, Numpy, git, Object Oriented Programming, GpyOpt

Artificial Intelligence: Computer Vision, Object Detection, Hyper Parameter Tuning, Natural Language

Processing, Transfer Learning, Time Series Forecasting **Deep Learning Frameworks:** Keras, TensorFlow, PyTorch

#### Education

Diploma in Computer Science and Machine Learning - Holberton - December 2023

• 20 month software engineering school where students learn through peer and project-based learning

B.S. Mechanical Engineering - Arkansas Tech University - 2010

A.S. Nuclear Technology - Arkansas Tech University - 2010

# Experience

Student Tutor - Holberton School - Tulsa, OK - August 2022 - Present

- Conducted bi-monthly live coding sessions for up to 80 students on upcoming concepts, offering guidance based on lessons and experiences gained through the initial learning of these concepts
- Provided 10 to 15 hours of weekly ad-hoc tutoring sessions for students covering Bash scripting, the C language, Python, and SQL

Senior Analyst, Engineering - Whirlpool - Tulsa, OK - March 2021 - April 2022

- Reduced press line down time from 75 minutes per day to 0 minutes per day by implementing light weight, modular robot end of arm tooling
- Led 15 people on the plant Focused Improvement team, driving increase in workforce engagement from 11% to 30% in 10 months

Engineering Manager - Carlisle Brake and Friction - June 2011 - December 2018

- Led a team of 10 Process Engineers in a manufacturing plant throughout a 2-year plant closure project, ensuring a 95%+ on-time delivery to customers while achieving annual savings of \$750,000
- Achieved a 10% reduction in monthly variable cost accruals through analysis of financial and manufacturing data, identifying misclassified costs, resulting in a 25% reduction in the time required to pinpoint improvement projects
- Served as a Site Subject Matter Expert and contributed to a global team responsible for the launch of a cloud-based software for global product lifecycle management

## **Projects**

Object Detection - YOLO V3 - April 2023 - Solo Project

Project Repo: <a href="https://github.com/bsbanotto/object\_detection">https://github.com/bsbanotto/object\_detection</a>
Technologies: Python, Tensorflow, CV2, Jupyter Notebook

- Created a custom implementation of YOLO V3 algorithm trained on the COCO dataset to detect objects in selected photographs
- Built bounding boxes to display confidences around identified objects

### **Bayesian Optimization**

Project Repo: <a href="https://github.com/bsbanotto/hyperparameter\_tuning">https://github.com/bsbanotto/hyperparameter\_tuning</a>
Technologies: Python, Jupyter Notebook, GpyOpt, Keras, TensorFlow

- Utilized Bayesian Optimization to fine tune a DenseNet-121 model for image classification on the imagenet dataset
- Improved validation accuracy on model by 10.5%

Space-Bubbles - December 2022 - Group Project Project Repo: <a href="https://github.com/bsbanotto/space-bubbles">https://github.com/bsbanotto/space-bubbles</a>

Technologies: Python, Pygame, SQLite

- Developed an emulator of Space Invaders mashed with Bubble Shooter during a four day sprint by working on a team with 2 peers
- Included a local leaderboard for high score tracking in a SQLite database